How well do we really know our parents?
‫ما مدى معرفتنا بوالدينا حقًا؟‬
Take my father.
‫أبي مثلًا. لطالما اعتبرته كتابًا مفتوحًا.‬
A man given to misguided schemes and exaggerated displays of affection.
‫رجل مستسلم للخطط المضللة‬ ‫والتعبير المُبالغ فيه عن المشاعر.‬
But when he was a student,
‫لكن حين كان طالبًا،‬
he was accused of a murder that took place right up there.
‫اتُهم بجريمة قتل وقعت هناك تمامًا.‬
Which leads me to wonder…
‫مما يقودني إلى التساؤل…‬
…what really happened that stormy night 32 years ago?
‫…عما حصل فعلًا في تلك الليلة العاصفة‬ ‫قبل 32 سنة؟‬
I think he had a sword, and they certainly have issues.
‫أظن أنه كان يحمل سيفًا،‬
I don't like to tell tales, Sheriff Walker,
‫لا أحب نشر الإشاعات أيها المأمور "واكر"،‬
but it's all Morticia Frump's fault.
‫لكن كلّ هذا خطأ "مورتيشا فرامب".‬
They were fighting over her.
‫كانا يتشاجران عليها.‬
Tish…
‫"تيش"…‬
I don't know what to say, Gomez.
‫لا أعرف ماذا أقول يا "غوميز".‬
Seeing you in handcuffs, accused of murder…
‫رؤيتك بالأغلال ومتهمًا بجريمة قتل…‬
I've never loved you more.
‫- لم أحبك بهذا القدر قط.‬ ‫- عزيزتي.‬
All right, that's enough, Addams.
‫حسنًا، هذا يكفي يا "آدامز". لنذهب.‬
-Let's move it out. Let's get going.
‫حسنًا، لننطلق. هيا بنا.‬
These were the best years of our lives, were they not, Tish?
‫كانت هذه أفضل سنوات حياتنا،‬ ‫أليس كذلك يا "تيش"؟‬
They certainly were, mi cariño.
‫لا شك في ذلك يا حبيبي.‬
I hope Wednesday's happy to see us.
‫آمل أن تسعد "وينزداي" برؤيتنا.‬
I left a dozen messages on her crystal ball. Still no reply.
‫تركت عشرات الرسائل لها‬ ‫على كرتها البلورية لكنها لم تجب.‬
Fret not, my plum-lipped cupid.
‫لا تقلقي يا ملاك حبي ممتلئ الشفتين!‬
I'm sure she's dying to see us.
‫أنا واثق بأنها تتحرق شوقًا لرؤيتنا.‬
Come on, let's go.
‫هيا بنا، لنذهب.‬
Nevermore was created as a safe haven for our children
‫تأسست "نيفرمور" لتكون ملاذًا آمنًا لأولادنا‬
to learn and to grow,
‫ليتعلموا وينموا،‬
no matter who or what they are.
‫أيًا كانوا ومهما كانوا.‬
I realize most of you have heard about
‫أعرف أن معظمكم قد سمع‬
the unfortunate incident involving one of our students.
‫عن الحادث المؤسف الذي طال أحد طلابنا.‬
But I'm happy to report that Eugene is on the mend
‫لكن يسعدني أن أبلّغكم‬ ‫أن "يوجين" يتماثل للشفاء،‬
and is expected to make a full recovery.
‫ونتوقع أن يتعافى بشكل كلّي.‬
So let's focus on the positive
‫لذا، لنركّز على الإيجابيات‬
and make this Parents' Weekend our very best yet.
‫ونجعل من عطلة الأسبوع مع الأهالي‬ ‫أفضل عطلة تشهدها المدرسة على الإطلاق.‬
On the mend?
‫يتماثل للشفاء؟‬
Try in a coma.
‫بل في غيبوبة.‬
Have you been to see him?
‫هل ذهبت لرؤيته؟‬
-You're his friend. -I'm the reason he's in the hospital.
‫أنت صديقته.‬
The monster hasn't attacked anyone in the past week.
‫لم يهاجم الوحش أحدًا في الأسبوع الماضي.‬
Maybe you finally scared it off.
‫ربما أخفته أخيرًا.‬
Or maybe it went into hiding to avoid this weekend.
‫أو ربما اختبأ‬ ‫لتفادي عطلة نهاية الأسبوع هذه.‬
Look at this. Some things never change.
‫انظر. بعض الأمور لا تتغير أبدًا.‬
I knew I should have worn my plague mask.
‫عرفت أنه كان يجب أن أضع قناع الوباء.‬
Would you look at my family?
‫انظري إلى عائلتي.‬
-Talk about toxic pack mentality.
‫هذه عقلية الزمرة السامة.‬
I give my mom 30 seconds before her judge-y claws come out.
‫أمنح أمي 30 ثانية‬ ‫قبل أن تخرج مخالبها الانتقادية.‬
There she is.
‫ها هي ذي.‬
Oh, how we missed those accusing eyes and youthful sneer.
‫كم اشتقنا إلى عينيك ونظرة الاتهام فيهما‬ ‫وشراسة الشباب!‬
How are you, my little rain cloud?
‫كيف حالك يا غمامتي الماطرة؟‬
I thought Thing was filling you in on my every move.
‫ظننت أن "ثينغ" يخبركما عن جميع تحركاتي.‬
I uncovered your feeble subterfuge almost immediately.
‫اكتشفت حيلتكما الضعيفة على الفور تقريبًا.‬
So, how's the little fella doing?
‫كيف حال الصغير إذًا؟‬
Does he still have all his fingers?
‫هل ما زال يحتفظ بأصابعه كلّها؟‬
Relax. I haven't snapped any of his digits.
‫اهدأ! لم أطقّ أيًا من أصابعه.‬
Yet.
‫ليس بعد.‬
So tell us everything.
‫أخبرينا كلّ شيء.‬
Since you've abandoned me here, I've been hunted, haunted…
‫منذ أن تخليتما عني هنا،‬
and the target of an attempted murder.
‫وكنت هدفًا لمحاولة قتل.‬
Enid.
‫"إينيد".‬
-One-one-thousand, two-one-thousand… -Have you not been waxing?
‫- 1000، 2000…‬ ‫- ألم تزيلي شعر جسدك؟‬
Three seconds. That's a personal best.
‫ثلاث ثوان! هذا رقم قياسي شخصي!‬
Are you feeling well? You're looking a touch anemic.
‫هل أنت بخير؟ تبدين مصابة بفقر الدم.‬
Have you been eating enough red meat?
‫هل تأكلين ما يكفي من اللحم الأحمر؟‬
It's good to see you too, Mom.
‫تسرني رؤيتك أيضًا يا أمي.‬
And you, Dad.
‫وأنت يا أبي.‬
Not sure how much more of this family togetherness I can take.
‫لا أعرف كم يمكنني‬ ‫أن أتحمّل هذه التجمعات العائلية بعد.‬
Think you skipped where you apologize for acting like a jerk last weekend.
‫أظن أنك تخطيت الاعتذار‬ ‫عن تصرفك كوغد في عطلة الأسبوع الماضي.‬
I'm sorry for what happened at the dance.
‫أعتذر على ما حصل في الحفل.‬
I shouldn't have asked you to siren-song me like that.
‫ما كان يجب أن أطلب منك أن تسحريني بغنائك.‬
Guessing your dad's a no-show again this year?
‫ألم يأت والدك هذه السنة أيضًا؟‬
Yeah.
‫صحيح.‬
I got a text this morning. You?
‫وصلتني رسالة منه صباح اليوم. ماذا عنك؟‬
Gabrielle hasn't shown her face since I started here.
‫لم تأت "غابرييل" إلى هنا‬ ‫منذ أن انضممت إلى المدرسة.‬
Probably sunning herself somewhere in the Seychelles.
‫لا بد أنها تسمّر بشرتها في مكان ما‬ ‫في جُزر "سيشل".‬
My darling daughter.
‫ابنتي العزيزة.‬
I made it.
‫لقد وصلت.‬
Wouldn't miss this for the world.
‫ما كنت لأفوّت هذا أبدًا.‬
I guess you misjudged her.
‫أظن أنك أسأت الحكم عليها.‬
Our old yearbook.
‫كتابنا السنوي القديم.‬
I haven't laid eyes on this in over 20 years.
‫لم أر هذا منذ أكثر من 20 عامًا.‬
Such good times we had, didn't we, Larissa?
‫أمضينا أوقاتًا ممتعة،‬ ‫أليس كذلك يا "لاريسا"؟‬
Some of us better than others.
‫البعض منا أكثر من سواهم.‬
Oh, don't be so modest.
‫كفى تواضعًا.‬
You always filled a room with your presence.
‫لطالما كان حضورك طاغيًا.‬
Like a stately sequoia tree.
‫كشجرة "سيكويا" متجذرة.‬
And I guess that would make you the lumberjack.
‫وأظن أن هذا يجعلك الحطّابة.‬
Do you remember when we did that duet for the Solstice Talent Show?
‫هل تذكرين حين قدّمنا أغنية ثنائية‬
Your Judy Garland impression was a dead ringer.
‫تقليدك لـ"جودي غارلند" كان خارقًا.‬
Sounds positively suicidal.
‫أمر انتحاري بامتياز!‬
My picture's gone.
‫اختفت صورتي.‬
Really? Well, that is odd.
‫حقًا؟ هذا غريب.‬
May I borrow this for the weekend?
‫أيمكنني أن أقترض هذا في عطلة الأسبوع؟‬
That way Gomez and I can take a little walk down memory lane.
‫هكذا يمكننا أنا و"غوميز"‬ ‫أن نسترجع ذكرياتنا.‬
All right.
‫حسنًا.‬
Unfortunately, Wednesday's assimilation has been rocky at best.
‫لسوء الحظ، إن اندماج "وينزداي" كان صعبًا.‬
Because I refuse to embrace
‫لأنني أرفض أن أتقبّل‬ ‫ثقافة الكذب والنكران المسيطرة على المدرسة.‬
Starting with the monster that killed Rowan and put Eugene in the ICU.
‫بدءًا بالوحش الذي قتل "روان"‬ ‫وأدخل "يوجين" إلى العناية الفائقة.‬
Although I do hear he's on the mend.
‫مع أنني سمعت أنه يتماثل للشفاء.‬
We've always encouraged Wednesday to speak her mind.
‫لطالما شجعنا "وينزداي"‬ ‫على التعبير عن رأيها.‬
Sometimes her sharp tongue can cut deep.
‫أحيانًا، يكون لسانها الحاد لاذعًا.‬
Apparently her therapist feels she hasn't been very open to the process.
‫يبدو أن معالجتها النفسية تشعر‬ ‫بأنها لم تكن منفتحة.‬
Their time together has not yielded the results we'd hoped.
‫وقت علاجها لم يولّد النتائج المرجوة.‬
I'm not a lab rat.
‫لست فأر تجارب.‬
Dr. Kinbott and I have spoken, and we both agree
‫تحدثت إلى الطبيبة "كينبوت" وكلتانا نتفق‬
it would be most beneficial for you all to attend a family session this weekend.
‫على أنه سيكون من المفيد لكم جميعًا‬ ‫أن تشاركوا في جلسة عائلية في عطلة الأسبوع.‬
No.
‫لا.‬
I thought that might be your reaction, but your parents can see the wisdom in it.
‫توقعت أن يكون هذا رد فعلك،‬ ‫لكن والديك يريان الحكمة في ذلك.‬
Oh, come on.
‫بحقك!‬
What can it hurt? To be honest,
‫ما الضير في ذلك؟ بصراحة،‬
I've always been a big fan of head-shrinking.
‫لطالما كنت من مشجعي العلاج النفسي الرأسي.‬
It's not that kind of head-shrinking, mon chéri.
‫ليس هذا النوع من العلاج النفسي الرأسي‬ ‫يا قلبي.‬
Well,
‫حسنًا…‬
that is disappointing.
‫هذا مخيب للآمال.‬
But anything for our little girl.
‫لكنني مستعد لأي شيء من أجل صغيرتنا.‬
Yeah.
‫أجل.‬
You make sure they search that cave for any sign of that creature.
‫احرص على أن يفتشوا ذاك الكهف‬ ‫بحثًا عن أي أثر لذاك المخلوق.‬
No stone unturned. They bag and tag everything, all right?
‫لا تتركوا حجرًا في مكانه.‬ ‫ليأخذوا أدلة عن كلّ شيء، اتفقنا؟‬
And then follow up with the lab. I want the DNA results on that claw.
‫ثم تابع مع المختبر. أريد نتائج‬ ‫تحليل الحمض النووي من ذاك المخلب.‬
We already got one kid in the ICU, a bunch of people in the morgue.
‫لدينا طالب في العناية الفائقة‬ ‫ومجموعة من الأشخاص في المشرحة.‬
I don't want any more.
‫لا أريد المزيد.‬
All right.
‫حسنًا.‬
Son of a bitch.
‫السافل!‬
What's wrong?
‫ما الخطب؟‬
Just hard to stomach a murderer wandering around town scot-free.
‫من الصعب أن أتقبّل وجود قاتل‬ ‫يتجول طليقًا في البلدة.‬
At least they care enough about Wednesday to go to therapy with her.
‫أقلّه يهتمون بما يكفي لـ"وينزداي"‬ ‫ليرافقوها إلى جلسة علاجية.‬
Tyler, come on. We've been through this.
‫"تايلر"، بحقك! سبق أن ناقشنا هذا.‬
I'm just… I'm not comfortable
‫لا أحبذ استرجاع ماضي العائلة مع شخص غريب.‬
Think it's easy for me to sit there and talk about my crap?
‫أتظن أنه من السهل بالنسبة إليّ‬ ‫أن أجلس هناك وأتحدث عن مشاكلي؟‬
You got the results already?
‫هل وصلتك النتائج؟‬
All right. Tape off the scene. I'll be right there.
‫حسنًا. أغلق موقع الجريمة. سآتي على الفور.‬
Dad. You okay? What's going on?
‫أبي. هل أنت بخير؟ ماذا يجري؟‬
You know Reggie, the local coroner?
‫أتعرف "ريجي"، الطبيب الشرعي المحلي؟‬
He just blew his brains out.
‫لقد أطلق النار على نفسه.‬
So, who wants to start?
‫إذًا، من يريد أن يبدأ؟‬
Maybe we can discuss what it's like having Wednesday away from home?
‫ربما يمكننا أن نتحدث عن شعوركم‬ ‫في ظل غياب "وينزداي" عن البيت.‬
I mean, for me…
‫بالنسبة إليّ،‬
I never thought I'd miss being waterboarded so much.
‫لم أظن قط‬ ‫أنني سأفتقد تعرضي للإيهام بالغرق كثيرًا.‬
Morticia, Gomez.
‫"مورتيشا" و"غوميز".‬
-How have you been coping? -It's been torture for us too.
‫- كيف تتعاملان مع الوضع؟‬ ‫- كنا نتعذب أيضًا.‬
Fortunately, my brother Fester's rack fits two people.
‫لحسن الحظ أن المخلعة الخاصة بأخي "فيستر"‬ ‫تتسع لشخصين.‬
Nothing like a good stretch to bring out the best in each other.
‫لا شيء يضاهي تمديدًا جيدًا‬ ‫لإخراج أفضل ما في الآخر.‬
Querida mía.
‫محبوبتي.‬
Enough!
‫هذا يكفي!‬
I think it's high time my parents faced the music.
‫أظن أنه حان الوقت ليواجه والداي الواقع.‬
It seems they've been lying to me.
‫يبدو أنهما كانا يكذبان عليّ.‬
Keeping secrets.
‫يكتمان الأسرار.‬
Murderous secrets that need to be addressed.
‫أسرار قاتلة يجب التحدث عنها.‬
Who was Garrett Gates, and why are you accused of murdering him?
‫من كان "غاريت غايتس" ولم أنت متهم بقتله؟‬
Those charges were dropped. Your father is an innocent man.
‫أُسقطت تلك التهم. والدك رجل بريء.‬
Local sheriff doesn't seem too convinced.
‫لا يبدو مأمور المنطقة مقتنعًا بذلك.‬
Wednesday, stop.
‫"وينزداي"، توقّفي.‬
This is neither the time nor the place.
‫لا الوقت ولا المكان مناسبان.‬
Actually, this is exactly the place.
‫في الواقع، المكان هو الأمثل.‬
-These sessions are-- -Doctor. This does not concern you.
‫- هذه الجلسات…‬ ‫- أيتها الطبيبة، هذا لا يعنيك.‬
And I refuse to debate a decades-old witch-hunt with you right now.
‫وأرفض أن أناقش معك‬ ‫صيد ساحرات يعود لعقود من الزمن.‬
-I-- -Darling, maybe we should--
‫- أنا…‬ ‫- عزيزتي، ربما يجدر بنا…‬
No. This session is over.
‫لا. انتهت الجلسة.‬
Have it your way, Mother.
‫كما تريدين يا أمي.‬
-Wednes… Wednesday? -If you refuse to tell me the truth,
‫- "وينزداي"؟‬ ‫- إن رفضت أن تخبريني الحقيقة،‬
I'll just have to excavate it myself.
‫فسيكون عليّ أن أنبشها بنفسي.‬
You…
‫أنتم…‬
Thanks for the candy.
‫شكرًا على السكاكر.‬
Actually, that's potpourri.
‫هذه أزهار مجففة.‬
Why don't you take the bowl?
‫لم لا تأخذ الوعاء؟‬
What were you thinking?
‫ما الذي كنت تفكرين فيه؟‬
How could you ambush your father like that? Wednesday.
‫كيف توقعين بوالدك هكذا؟ "وينزداي".‬
How could I? You insisted I go to this school.
‫كيف أمكنني ذلك؟‬ ‫أصررتما على ارتيادي هذه المدرسة.‬
Did you really think I wouldn't find out your secret?
‫هل ظننتما أنني لن أعرف سركما؟‬
You don't know the full story. Your father did nothing wrong.
‫لا تعرفين القصة كاملةً.‬
I'll be the judge of that.
‫أنا سأقرر ذلك.‬
Potpourri?
‫أزهار مجففة؟‬
How did you find me?
‫كيف وجدتني؟‬
MorningSong community misses you.
‫تفتقدك جمعية "أغنية الصباح".‬
I miss you.
‫أنا أفتقدك.‬
And by community, you mean cult?
‫وبقولك جمعية، هل تقصدين طائفة؟‬
We are a personal development movement
‫نحن حركة تطوير شخصية‬
that helps people take control of their lives.
‫تساعد الناس على التحكم بحياتهم.‬
After you take control of their bank accounts.
‫بعد أن تتحكمي بحساباتهم المصرفية.‬
I haven't come here to fight, Brandy Jane.
‫لم آت إلى هنا لنتشاجر يا "براندي جاين".‬
My name is Bianca.
‫اسمي "بيانكا".‬
New name. New life.
‫اسم جديد. حياة جديدة.‬
It's time to come home.
‫حان وقت العودة إلى الديار.‬
That place was never my home.
‫لم يكن ذاك المكان دياري قط.‬
-Gideon said you'd resist. -Don't say that man's name to me.
‫- قال "غيديون" إنك ستقاومين.‬ ‫- لا تقولي اسم ذلك الرجل أمامي.‬
-if we weren't sirens?
‫لو لم نكن سيرانتين؟‬
That is no way to talk about your stepfather.
‫لا يليق أن تتحدثي عن زوج أمك بهذا الأسلوب.‬
You actually married him.
‫لقد تزوجته حقًا.‬
He wants you to come home, so that we can be a real family.
‫يريدك أن تعودي إلى البيت‬ ‫لنكون عائلة حقيقية.‬
Hard pass.
‫أرفض بشدة.‬
He's already got one siren to do his bidding.
‫لديه سيرانة بالفعل لتنفذ مطالبه.‬
Goodbye, Ma.
‫وداعًا يا أمي.‬
I don't want to see more MorningSong bracelets anywhere near this town.
‫لا أريد أن أرى أساور "أغنية الصباح"‬ ‫في أي مكان قرب هذه البلدة بعد الآن.‬
My siren song is drying up.
‫أغنيتي كسيرانة تنضب.‬
Recruitment numbers are down,
‫أعداد الانتساب تتراجع،‬
and the wrong people are starting to ask questions.
‫وبدأ الأشخاص غير المناسبين يطرحون الأسئلة.‬
This wasn't a request.
‫لم أكن أطلب منك.‬
And if I refuse?
‫وإن رفضت؟‬
Then everybody here is gonna know how you siren'd your way into Nevermore.
‫إذًا سيعرف الجميع هنا‬ ‫أنك دخلت إلى "نيفرمور" باستخدام قدراتك.‬
I finally make something of myself and you want to destroy it.
‫بنيت أخيرًا شيئًا لنفسي وتريدين أن تهدميه.‬
You haven't made squat, Bianca.
‫لم تفعلي شيئًا يا "بيانكا".‬
You're just scamming a higher class of people,
‫أنت تخدعين أشخاصًا من طبقة أعلى،‬ ‫لكنهم ليسوا أصدقاءك.‬
Sooner or later they will see through you.
‫عاجلًا أم آجلًا، سيرونك على حقيقتك.‬
A siren can never change her scales.
‫لا تستطيع سيرانة أن تغير طبيعتها.‬
You got until the end of the weekend to say your goodbyes.
‫أمامك حتى نهاية عطلة الأسبوع‬ ‫لتودّعي أصدقاءك.‬
I harvested hive number three.
‫جمعت العسل من القفير رقم ثلاثة.‬
The bees miss you, Eugene.
‫تفتقدك النحلات يا "يوجين".‬
We all do.
‫كلّنا نفتقدك.‬
Thanks for keeping an eye on him.
‫أشكرك على الاعتناء به.‬
Any updates?
‫هل من مستجدات؟‬
He didn't deserve this.
‫لم يكن يستحق هذا.‬
I should be in that bed.
‫يجب أن أكون مكانه في ذلك السرير.‬
Why did you go without me?
‫لماذا ذهبت من دوني؟‬
-Didn't mean to startle you, dear. -You must be Wednesday.
‫لم أقصد أن أخيفك يا عزيزتي.‬
Eugene's moms. Sue and Janet.
‫نحن أمّا "يوجين"، "سو" و"جانيت".‬
You were all he could talk about lately.
‫لم يتكلّم إلّا عنك في الفترة الأخيرة.‬
He was so happy you joined the Hummers.
‫كان سعيدًا جدًا‬ ‫بانضمامك إلى نادي "الطنانات".‬
Eugene hasn't had the easiest time fitting in at Nevermore.
‫واجه "يوجين" صعوبة‬ ‫في التأقلم في "نيفرمور".‬
He was so excited to finally make a real friend.
‫كان متحمسًا جدًا‬ ‫لكونه وجد صديقة حقيقية أخيرًا.‬
I brought him some honey.
‫أحضرت له بعض العسل.‬
Eugene loves those dang bees like they're his kids.
‫يحب "يوجين" تلك النحلات كأنها فلذة كبده.‬
His fuzzy-buzzy babies.
‫طفلاته الزغبة!‬
He's gonna be okay, right?
‫سيكون بخير، صحيح؟‬
I should go.
‫يجب أن أذهب.‬
First time someone's killed themselves in the morgue.
‫إنها المرة الأولى التي ينتحر فيها أحد‬ ‫في المشرحة.‬
Guys don't know what to do with the body.
‫لا يعرف الموظفون ماذا يفعلون بالجثة.‬
-What do you got? -Gun was legal and registered in his name.
‫ماذا لديك؟‬
Janitor said he kept it in his desk.
‫قال الحاجب إنه كان يبقيه في مكتبه.‬
I just saw Doc last week.
‫رأيت الطبيب الأسبوع الماضي.‬
He was planning a cruise with his wife. He seemed excited all about retirement.
‫كان يخطط للذهاب في رحلة بحرية مع زوجته.‬ ‫بدا متحمسًا جدًا بشأن التقاعد.‬
Guess you never know what's going through someone's mind.
‫لا أحد يعرف ماذا يجري في عقل الناس.‬
A bullet, apparently. We got security footage?
‫رصاصة على ما يبدو.‬ ‫هل لدينا مشاهد المراقبة؟‬
Nope. Camera was obscured. Black bubblegum.
‫لا. كانت الكاميرا محجوبة. علكة سوداء.‬
I got them scrubbing through video to find out how long it's been there.
‫جعلتهم يراجعون الشريط‬ ‫ليعرفوا كم مضى على وجودها.‬
Black bubblegum.
‫علكة سوداء.‬
You don't say…
‫عجبًا!‬
The suicide note says he felt guilty about an old case.
‫ورد في رسالة الانتحار أنه شعر بالذنب‬ ‫بسبب قضية قديمة.‬
Says he covered it up, faked the coroner's report,
‫قال إنه تستّر على الأمر وزوّر تقرير التشريح،‬
and has been living with guilt for all these years.
‫وأنه كان يعيش مع ذنبه طوال سنوات.‬
What case?
‫أي قضية؟‬
Uh, Garrett Gates.
‫"غاريت غايتس".‬
Garrett Gates. You gotta be kidding me.
‫"غاريت غايتس". لا بد أنك تمازحينني.‬
I've been waiting 30 years to put away his murderer.
‫أنتظر منذ 30 عامًا لأعتقل قاتله.‬
You know who did it?
‫أتعرف من فعل ذلك؟‬
There's only ever been one suspect.
‫لم يكن هناك سوى مشتبه به واحد.‬
I always thought they were covering up the truth.
‫لطالما ظننت أنهم يتسترون على الحقيقة.‬
Now I got my proof.
‫والآن، أصبح لديّ دليل.‬
You're not hungry, darling?
‫ألست جائعة يا عزيزتي؟‬
My appetite eludes me, Mother.
‫غابت عني شهيتي يا أمي.‬
The same way the truth eludes you.
‫تمامًا كما غابت عنك الحقيقة.‬
We need to tell her.
‫يجب أن نخبرها.‬
She'll never believe us.
‫لن تصدقنا أبدًا.‬
We must stay strong.
‫يجب أن نبقى قويين.‬
And hope that something more morbid comes along to distract her.
‫ونأمل أن يحدث شيء محبط أكثر لتشتيتها.‬
So are you going to make me ask?
‫هل ستجعلينني أسأل؟‬
Ajax and I haven't defined our relationship yet.
‫أنا و"إيجاكس" لم نحدد طبيعة علاقتنا بعد.‬
I'm not talking about boys.
‫لا أتكلم عن الفتيان.‬
Have you wolfed out yet?
‫هل تحولت إلى ذئب بعد؟‬
No.
‫لا.‬
Well, that is a disappointment.
‫هذه خيبة أمل.‬
That's me.
‫هذه أنا.‬
A huge disappointment.
‫خيبة أمل كبيرة.‬
Can I ask what this is about, Sheriff?
‫أيمكنني أن أعرف ما سبب هذا أيها المأمور؟‬
What's happening, Ms. Thornhill?
‫ماذا يحدث يا آنسة "ثورنهيل"؟‬
I have no idea.
‫لا أعرف.‬
Gomez Addams.
‫"غوميز آدامز".‬
How can I help you, Sheriff?
‫كيف أساعدك أيها المأمور؟‬
You're under arrest for the murder of Garrett Gates.
‫أنت رهن الاعتقال بتهمة قتل "غاريت غايتس".‬
You have the right to remain silent.
‫يحق لك التزام الصمت.‬
Anything you say can and will be used against you in a court of law.
‫كلّ ما تقوله يمكن أن يُستخدم‬ ‫وسيُستخدم ضدك في المحكمة.‬
Dad?
‫أبي؟‬
You have the right to an attorney.
‫يحق لك أن توكّل محاميًا.‬
If you cannot afford one, one will be appointed for you.
‫إن لم يكن بوسعك تحمّل أجرة محام،‬ ‫فسيتم تعيين واحد لك.‬
My little tormenta, how's your mother?
‫عاصفتي الصغيرة، كيف حال أمك؟‬
Devastated. She hates you in orange.
‫إنها محطمة. تكرهك باللون البرتقالي.‬
I caught her laying a rose on a grave earlier today.
‫رأيتها تضع وردة على قبر اليوم.‬
The headstone read "Garrett Gates."
‫كُتب على شاهد القبر "غاريت غايتس".‬
The very boy you've been arrested for murdering.
‫الصبي نفسه الذي اعتقلوك بتهمة قتله.‬
Care to explain?
‫هل تريد أن تشرح؟‬
Garrett was infatuated with your mother.
‫كان "غاريت" مفتونًا بأمك.‬
He mistook her kindness for interest.
‫وظن أن طيبتها تعني أنها معجبة به.‬
His infatuation turned into obsession,
‫وتحوّل افتتانه بها إلى هوس.‬
and he started stalking her.
‫بدأ يترصدها.‬
-Why didn't you call the police? -We tried.
‫- لماذا لم تتصلا بالشرطة؟‬ ‫- حاولنا.‬
But his family were the oldest and richest in Jericho.
‫لكن كانت عائلته الأقدم والأغنى‬ ‫في "جيريكو".‬
No one believed us.
‫لم يصدقنا أحد.‬
Garrett's father, an outcast-hating bigot,
‫والد "غاريت"، وهو متعصب يكره المنبوذين،‬
was furious that your mother had accused his only son.
‫استشاط غضبًا لأن أمك اتهمت ابنه الوحيد.‬
It all came to a head the night of the Rave'N Dance.
‫وكانت المواجهة في ليلة حفلة "ذا رايف إن".‬
Your mother and I stepped out to catch our breath.
‫خرجنا أنا وأمك لنلتقط أنفاسنا.‬
Addams!
‫"آدامز"!‬
And that's when I saw him.
‫وحينها رأيته.‬
He had broken into the school.
‫كان قد اقتحم المدرسة.‬
His twisted love for your mother had made him insane.
‫حبه المنحرف لأمك أفقده صوابه.‬
His eyes bore into me, brimming with murderous intent.
‫حدّق إليّ بعينيه وشرارة القتل تنبثق منهما.‬
Go. Get out of here. He won't hurt me.
‫اذهب! ارحل من هنا. لن يؤذيني.‬
Garrett, no!
‫"غاريت"، لا!‬
Garrett, stop!
‫"غاريت"، توقّف!‬
My life flashed before my eyes.
‫رأيت الموت بعينيّ.‬
Driven by jealousy and hate, Garrett was unstoppable.
‫كان منقادًا وراء الغيرة والكراهية،‬
When I saw the sword,
‫عندما رأيت السيف،‬
my survival instinct kicked in.
‫اشتعلت فيّ غريزة البقاء.‬
It was a terrible accident.
‫كان حادثًا فظيعًا.‬
If I'm being objective, his confession sounds entirely plausible,
‫إن فكرت بموضوعية،‬
delivered with the perfect degree of sincerity.
‫ولقد أخبرني بدرجة مثالية من الصدق.‬
Perhaps my father is exactly what he says.
‫ربما أبي هو بالضبط كما يقول.‬
Thank you for being honest with me.
‫أشكرك على صدقك.‬
But then there's the matter of his tells.
‫لكن تبقى مسألة الإشارات التي يقوم بها.‬
The way he smooths his mustache.
‫كيفية تمسيده لشاربه.‬
The way he delivers a comforting wink.
‫كيفية غمزه بطريقة تبعث الراحة.‬
I've been playing Russian roulette with him since I was 12.
‫ألعب "روليت" روسية معه‬ ‫منذ أن كنت في الـ12.‬
I know them well.
‫أعرف حركاته.‬
I'm sorry I wasn't a better father.
‫آسف لأنني لم أكن أبًا أفضل.‬
Could we please do without the overt display of emotion?
‫أيمكننا الاستغناء‬ ‫عن عرض المشاعر المُبالغ فيه؟‬
I know they make you feel uncomfortable.
‫أعرف أن المشاعر تشعرك بالانزعاج.‬
How many fathers hand their daughter a fencing blade when she's five?
‫كم من الآباء يعطون ابنتهم سيف مبارزة‬ ‫في الخامسة من عمرها؟‬
Your saber strokes were an essay in perfection.
‫كانت ضربات السيف خاصتك عنوان المثالية.‬
Or teach her how to swim with sharks?
‫أو يعلّمها أن تسبح مع أسماك القرش؟‬
They found you as cold-blooded as I do.
‫وجدتك باردة الدماء وقاسية مثلي.‬
The right way to flay a rattlesnake?
‫والطريقة الصحيحة لسلخ أفعى مجلجلة؟‬
They really do taste like chicken when prepared properly.
‫مذاقها كالدجاج حقًا‬ ‫حين تُعدّ بالطريقة الصحيحة.‬
The point is, you taught me how to be strong and independent.
‫المقصود هو أنك علّمتني‬ ‫أن أكون قوية ومستقلة.‬
How to navigate myself in a world full of treachery and prejudice.
‫كيف أتدبّر أمري‬ ‫في عالم مليء بالخيانة والأحكام المسبقة.‬
You are the reason I understand how imperative it is
‫أنت السبب في كوني أفهم‬ ‫مدى ضرورة ألّا أنسى نفسي أبدًا.‬
So as far as fatherhood goes, I would say you've been more than adequate.
‫لذا، بالنسبة إلى الأبوة،‬ ‫أظن أنك كنت أكثر من ممتاز.‬
Gracias, Wednesday.
‫شكرًا يا "وينزداي".‬
We need to talk.
‫علينا أن نتحدث.‬
How the hell did you get in?
‫كيف دخلت بحق الجحيم؟‬
Bernice? Bernice!
‫"بيرنيس"؟‬
Bernice may or may not have received a call that her tabby cat Swifty
‫ربما تكون "بيرنيس" قد تلقت اتصالًا‬ ‫بأن قطتها "سويفتي" محتجزة مقابل فدية.‬
My father did not kill Garrett Gates.
‫لم يقتل أبي "غاريت غايتس".‬
Well, I have his signed confession,
‫معي اعترافه الموقّع،‬
and he identified the saber he used to do it.
‫ولقد تعرّف على السيف الذي استخدمه لقتله.‬
Both of which I'm about to deliver to the District Attorney.
‫وسأسلّم الاثنين إلى مكتب المدعي العام.‬
Don't you find the timing convenient?
‫ألا تجد الوقت غريبًا بعض الشيء؟‬
The coroner kills himself out of remorse for a decades-old murder case
‫ينتحر الطبيب الشرعي بسبب الندم‬ ‫على قضية قديمة تعود إلى عقود ماضية‬
the very weekend my father, your prime suspect,
‫في عطلة الأسبوع نفسها التي يعود فيها أبي،‬ ‫المشتبه به الرئيسي، إلى البلدة.‬
All I see is a guilty man who's finally going to pay for his crime.
‫لا أرى سوى رجل مذنب‬ ‫سيدفع أخيرًا ثمن جريمته.‬
And cuffing him myself, oh, that was the icing on the cake.
‫وتكبيله بنفسي كان مكافأة إضافية.‬
How are you failing to see that someone is
‫كيف لا ترى أن أحدهم‬
desperately trying to derail my investigation?
‫يحاول يائسًا إفساد تحقيقي؟‬
I found the monster's cave, and I gave you the DNA evidence.
‫وجدت كهف الوحش وأعطيتك دليل حمض نووي.‬
Did you even bother to test it?
‫أتكبدت عناء إجراء التحليل أساسًا؟‬
This may come as a shock, but the world doesn't revolve around you.
‫قد يصدمك الأمر،‬ ‫لكن العالم لا يدور من حولك.‬
Here. DNA results.
‫تفضلي. نتائج تحليل الحمض النووي.‬
No match. Inconclusive.
‫لا تطابق. نتيجة غير حاسمة.‬
So you truly believe this is all some coincidence?
‫أتظن حقًا أن هذه مصادفة؟‬
Whoever hurt Eugene also murdered the coroner.
‫من آذى "يوجين" قتل الطبيب الشرعي أيضًا.‬
Unfortunately, someone sabotaged the security camera in the morgue,
‫للأسف،‬ ‫عطّل أحدهم كاميرا المراقبة في المشرحة‬
so we don't know what happened.
‫ولا نعرف ماذا حصل.‬
They stuck bubblegum on the lens.
‫ألصقوا علكة على العدسة.‬
Black bubblegum.
‫علكة سوداء.‬
Maybe I should run DNA on that?
‫هل أجري تحليل حمض نووي عليها؟‬
Someone is trying to throw me off my game. This is all a distraction.
‫يحاول أحدهم إرباكي. هذا كلّه مجرد تشتيت.‬
No, this is about justice being served.
‫لا، بل يتعلق الأمر بإحلال العدالة.‬
Garrett Gates's family deserves closure,
‫تستحق عائلة "غاريت غايتس" خاتمة،‬
even if none of them are around to take comfort in it.
‫حتى إن لم يكن أي منهم موجودًا‬ ‫لإيجاد الراحة بسببها.‬
What happened to them?
‫ماذا حدث لهم؟‬
His mother hung herself in the backyard.
‫شنقت أمه نفسها في الباحة الخلفية.‬
His father drank himself to an early grave.
‫ثمل والده حتى الموت.‬ ‫حتى أخته الصغرى لم تنج.‬
She was orphaned, sent overseas, ended up drowning.
‫أصبحت يتيمة وأُرسلت إلى الخارج وغرقت.‬
Every last one of them's gone.
‫مات كلّ فرد منهم.‬
Your father doesn't just have Garrett's blood on his hands,
‫لم يلوث والدك يديه بدماء "غاريت" وحسب،‬
he's got the whole damn family's.
‫بل بدماء العائلة كلّها.‬
Here. I brought you a gift.
‫تفضلي. أحضرت لك هدية.‬
That's so sweet. You didn't have to get me anything.
‫هذا لطف منك.‬
I know, but I thought we got off on the wrong foot this weekend.
‫أعرف،‬
I just want you to know that all I want is the very best for you.
‫أريدك أن تعرفي أنني أريد الأفضل لك.‬
What are these?
‫ما هذه؟‬
Brochures.
‫كتيبات.‬
For summer camp.
‫لمخيم صيفي.‬
These aren't just ordinary summer camps.
‫هذه ليست مخيمات صيفية عادية.‬
These are camps for lycanthropy conversion.
‫هذه مخيمات للتحول الذئبي.‬
Oh, no need to be dramatic, Enid.
‫لا داعي لأن تكوني درامية يا "إينيد".‬
You want to send me to conversion therapy for werewolves?
‫أتريدين إرسالي‬ ‫إلى مخيم لعلاج تحوّل المستذئبين؟‬
It worked wonders for your cousin Lucille, didn't it?
‫حقق نتائج مذهلة مع قريبتك "لوسيل"،‬ ‫أليس كذلك؟‬
Seven weeks in the Balkan countryside
‫أمضت سبعة أسابيع في ريف "البلقان"‬ ‫وبدأت تعوي للقمر بسرعة.‬
As it should be.
‫كما يجب أن يحصل.‬
Don't you want to wolf out and finally be normal, honey?
‫ألا تريدين أن تتحولي إلى ذئب‬ ‫وتصبحي طبيعية أخيرًا يا عزيزتي؟‬
Go away.
‫ارحلي.‬
You forgot your fishing gear.
‫نسيت عدة الصيد.‬
Stop trying to be nice.
‫كفّي عن محاولة التصرف بلطف.‬
It doesn't suit you.
‫هذا لا يناسبك.‬
Father packed your favorite bait.
‫أحضر أبي الطُعم المفضل لديك.‬
What'll happen to him now?
‫ماذا سيحدث له الآن؟‬
Well, he's confessed, so there won't be a trial.
‫لقد اعترف، لذا لن تكون هناك محاكمة.‬
After he's sentenced, he'll be sent to a state penitentiary,
‫بعد أن يصدر الحكم بحقه،‬ ‫سيُرسل إلى سجن الولاية‬
where he'll lose his mind being separated from Mother.
‫حيث سيفقد عقله لافتراقه عن أمي.‬
Did you know they haven't spent a night apart since they tied the knot?
‫هل تعرف أنهما لم يمضيا ليلة مفترقين‬ ‫منذ أن تزوجا؟‬
I always thought I'd be the first one in the family behind bars.
‫لطالما ظننت أنني سأكون أول فرد من العائلة‬ ‫يدخل السجن.‬
Lurch and I had a bet going.
‫كان بيني وبين "لورتش" رهان.‬
Come on. Let's see if the fish are biting.
‫هيا. لنر إن كانت الأسماك ستلتقط الطُعم.‬
That's quite a catch.
‫يا له من صيد!‬
I'm gonna miss him, Wednesday.
‫سأفتقده يا "وينزداي"!‬
It's not over yet. He's innocent.
‫لم ينته الأمر بعد. إنه بريء.‬
Well,
‫حسنًا،‬
if anyone can figure out who really committed the crime…
‫إن كان هناك من يستطيع أن يكتشف‬ ‫من ارتكب الجريمة فعلًا،‬
it's you.
‫فهو أنت.‬
Well, until that happens, we both know Mother will be falling apart.
‫وبانتظار حدوث ذلك،‬ ‫كلانا يعرف أن أمنا ستنهار.‬
Which means we have to be strong.
‫مما يعني أن علينا أن نكون قويين.‬
And by "we," I mean you.
‫وبكلامي هذا أقصدك أنت.‬
Now, give me one of those.
‫الآن، أعطني واحدة من هذه.‬
Where is Mother anyway?
‫أين أمي أساسًا؟‬
She said she wanted to be alone.
‫قالت إنها تريد أن تكون بمفردها.‬
Somewhere where no one would find her.
‫في مكان حيث لا يجدها أحد.‬
Hello, Mother.
‫مرحبًا يا أمي.‬
Hello, Wednesday.
‫مرحبًا يا "وينزداي".‬
So you're a Nightshade.
‫إذًا أنت عضو في "نايتشايد".‬
That didn't take long.
‫لم يستغرق ذلك وقتًا طويلًا.‬
Actually, I rejected them.
‫في الواقع، لقد رفضتهم.‬
Why? Because I was a member?
‫لماذا؟ ألأنني كنت عضوًا؟‬
I'll never live up to your legacy here,
‫لن أرتقي أبدًا إلى مستوى إرثك هنا،‬
so why try?
‫فلم أحاول؟‬
I win the Poe Cup, you claimed it four times.
‫فزت بمسابقة كأس "بو"،‬ ‫لكنك فزت به أربع مرات.‬
I join the fencing team, you captained it.
‫انضممت إلى فريق المبارزة،‬ ‫لكنك كنت قائدة الفريق.‬
Why would you send me somewhere I could only ever exist in your shadow?
‫لماذا أرسلتني إلى مكان‬ ‫لا يمكنني أن أعيش فيه إلّا في ظلك؟‬
It's not a competition, Wednesday.
‫ليست منافسة يا "وينزداي".‬
Everything is a competition, Mother.
‫كلّ شيء منافسة يا أمي.‬
But mostly I rejected them because they're a trivial social club.
‫لكنني رفضتهم في الغالب‬ ‫لأنه ناد اجتماعي تافه.‬
We used to be so much more.
‫كنا أكثر من ذلك بكثير.‬
Our mission was to protect outcasts from harm and bigotry.
‫كانت مهمتنا حماية المنبوذين‬ ‫من الأذى والتعصب.‬
In fact, the group was started by an ancestor of your father's from Mexico.
‫في الواقع، تأسست المجموعة‬ ‫على يد أحد أسلاف والدك من "المكسيك".‬
One of the first settlers in America.
‫من المستوطنين الأوائل في "أمريكا".‬
Goody.
‫"غودي".‬
I saw her painting at Pilgrim World.
‫رأيت رسمًا لها في "عالم الحجاج".‬
How ironic, since she was the one who killed Joseph Crackstone.
‫يا لسخرية ذلك‬ ‫بما أنها من قتلت "جوزيف كراكستون".‬
The Nightshades were her secret, but deadly, answer to his oppression.
‫كان نادي "نايتشايد" سرّها،‬ ‫لكنه كان حلًا قاتلًا لقمعه.‬
I know why you've come here, Wednesday.
‫أعرف سبب مجيئك إلى هنا يا "وينزداي".‬
So go on. Ask.
‫فتفضلي. سليني.‬
Father didn't kill Garrett Gates, did he?
‫لم يقتل أبي "غاريت غايتس"، صحيح؟‬
No.
‫لا.‬
By the time I made it up the stairs,
‫حين وصلت إلى أعلى السلّم،‬
I found your father fighting for his life. It was terrifying.
‫وجدت والدك يناضل للدفاع عن حياته.‬ ‫شعرت بالرعب.‬
Garrett, no!
‫"غاريت"، لا!‬
Garrett!
‫"غاريت"!‬
Garrett, stop!
‫"غاريت"، توقّف!‬
Leave him alone!
‫دعه وشأنه!‬
I'll never forget the way he looked at me.
‫لن أنسى أبدًا كيف نظر إليّ.‬
He was even foaming at the mouth.
‫حتى أنه كان يفرز رغوة من فمه.‬
It was like I was staring into the eyes of a rabid beast.
‫كأنني كنت أحدق إلى عيني وحش مسعور.‬
Oh, no.
‫لا.‬
It was only when I heard the scream
‫لم أدرك ما فعلته إلّا حين سمعت الصراخ.‬
Your father was so…
‫كان والدك…‬
calm and brave.
‫هادئًا وشجاعًا جدًا.‬
Tish, you need to leave right now.
‫"تيش"، يجب أن تغادري الآن.‬
Go to your room and lock the door.
‫اذهبي إلى غرفتك وأغلقي الباب.‬
You were never here.
‫لم تكوني هنا قط.‬
-You understand me?
‫هل تفهمين؟‬
Morticia?
‫"مورتيشا"؟‬
Put this back on the table.
‫أعيدي هذا إلى الطاولة.‬
-Go. -Okay.
‫- اذهبي.‬ ‫- حسنًا.‬
Your father took the blame in order to protect me.
‫تحمّل والدك الملامة كي يحميني.‬
I was so grateful when they cleared him of any wrongdoing.
‫كنت ممتنة جدًا حين تمت تبرئته من أي جرم.‬
But I knew,
‫لكنني عرفت،‬
someday this would come back to haunt us.
‫أنه يومًا ما، سيعود ما حصل ويقضّ مضجعنا.‬
You said Garrett was foaming at the mouth.
‫قلت إن "غاريت" كان يفرز رغوة من فمه،‬
His eyes didn't look human.
‫وإن عينيه لم تبدوا بشريتين.‬
I've never seen someone so blinded by rage.
‫لم أر شخصًا يعميه الغضب هكذا من قبل.‬
Maybe it wasn't rage at all.
‫ربما لم يكن غضبًا.‬
Foaming saliva, dilated pupils, mental confusion.
‫إفراز لعاب رغوي وبؤبؤان متسعان‬ ‫وارتباك عقلي.‬
What are those all textbook symptoms of?
‫هذه علامات تقليدية لأي شيء؟‬
But how can that be?
‫لكن كيف يُعقل ذلك؟‬
There's only one way to find out.
‫هناك طريقة واحدة لمعرفة ذلك.‬
You were so happy, you nearly smiled.
‫كنت سعيدة جدًا وكدت تبتسمين.‬
Are you sure you don't want to join?
‫ألا تريدين الانضمام إليّ؟‬
Moment of truth.
‫لحظة الحقيقة.‬
Hello, Garrett.
‫مرحبًا يا "غاريت".‬
I was right.
‫كنت محقة.‬
Well, well, what do we have here?
‫عجبًا، ماذا لدينا هنا؟‬
Guess there's gonna be an Addams family reunion
‫أرى أنه سيكون لمّ شمل لعائلة "آدامز"‬ ‫في السجن الليلة.‬
You're both under arrest.
‫كلتاكما رهن الاعتقال.‬
Get comfortable. You can post bail in the morning.
‫ارتاحا.‬ ‫يمكنكما أن تدفعا الكفالة في الصباح.‬
Not even the long arm of the law could keep us apart.
‫حتى ذراع القانون الطويلة‬ ‫لم تستطع أن تفرّق بيننا.‬
At least we'll have one last night together.
‫- أقلّه سنحظى بليلة أخرى معًا.‬ ‫- نعم.‬
I've seen jackals with more self-control than you two.
‫رأيت ثعالب تسيطر على نفسها أكثر منكما.‬
Neither one of you are strong enough to serve hard time.
‫كلاكما لستما قويين بما يكفي‬ ‫لقضاء عقوبة قاسية في السجن.‬
And thanks to me, you won't have to.
‫لكن بفضلي، لن يكون عليكما ذلك.‬
I knew our little jailbird would have an escape plan.
‫عرفت أنه سيكون لدى سجينتنا الصغيرة‬ ‫خطة للفرار.‬
It's a souvenir from our outing. I borrowed it from Garrett.
‫إنها ذكرى من نزهتنا. اقترضتها من "غاريت".‬
He died from nightshade poisoning.
‫مات جرّاء تسمم بزهرة "نايتشايد".‬
The remarkable preservation of soft tissue and blue tint confirms it.
‫وما يؤكد ذلك هو الأنسجة اللينة‬ ‫المحفوظة بشكل مبهر والصباغ الأزرق.‬
-Which means Garrett was dying-- -Before you stabbed him.
‫- مما يعني أن "غاريت" كان يحتضر…‬ ‫- قبل أن تطعنيه.‬
You look even more ravishing as an innocent woman.
‫تبدين أكثر سحرًا كامرأة بريئة.‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
For once, could you two get off of each other and focus.
‫لمرة واحدة،‬ ‫أيمكنكما الابتعاد عن بعضكما والتركيز؟‬
Prove to me you're still worthy to be called my son!
‫أثبت لي أنك ما زلت تستحق أن تُدعى ابني!‬
Kill all those outcasts!
‫اقتل المنبوذين كلّهم!‬
Sneak into that dance and spike the punch bowl.
‫تسلل إلى الحفل الراقص‬ ‫وأضف هذا السم إلى المشروب.‬
Addams!
‫"آدامز"!‬
Wednesday.
‫"وينزداي".‬
Did you have a vision?
‫هل راودتك رؤية؟‬
What happened?
‫ماذا حدث؟‬
What did you see?
‫ماذا رأيت؟‬
The night Garrett died,
‫ليلة مقتل "غاريت"،‬
He wasn't just trying to kill father.
‫لم يكن يحاول قتل أبي فحسب.‬
He was going to use the nightshade poison to murder the entire school.
‫كان سيستخدم سم "نايتشايد"‬ ‫ليقتل طلاب المدرسة كلّهم.‬
Thank you for seeing us at such short notice, Mr. Mayor.
‫أشكرك على مقابلتنا‬ ‫رغم المهلة القصيرة يا حضرة العمدة.‬
Yes, well, veiled threats have that effect.
‫أجل، للتهديدات المبطنة تأثير.‬
Garrett Gates wasn't killed by a stab wound.
‫لم يُقتل "غاريت غايتس" بطعنة.‬
That blue sheen is a telltale sign of nightshade poisoning.
‫الصباغ الأزرق‬ ‫هو علامة التسمم بزهرة "نايتشايد".‬
But you already knew that, didn't you?
‫لكنك تعرف ذلك، صحيح؟‬
Because back when you were sheriff,
‫لأنك عندما كنت المأمور،‬
you were in charge and covered it up.
‫كنت المسؤول وتسترت على الأمر.‬
Ansel Gates hated outcasts and Nevermore.
‫كره "أنسيل غايتس" المنبوذين و"نيفرمور".‬
was stolen from his family over 200 years ago.
‫سُرقت من عائلته قبل أكثر من 200 سنة.‬
Garrett went there that night to spike the punch
‫ذهب "غاريت" إلى المدرسة في تلك الليلة‬ ‫لدسّ السم في المشروب‬
and kill all the kids at that dance.
‫وقتل جميع الطلاب في الحفل.‬
Ansel confessed the whole thing to me in a drunken stupor. It was his idea.
‫اعترف لي "أنسيل" بكلّ شيء‬ ‫تحت تأثير الثمالة.‬
Why did you instruct Dr. Anwar to falsify the autopsy report?
‫لماذا طلبت من الطبيب "أنوار"‬ ‫تزييف تقرير التشريح؟‬
You knew the truth about how he really died.
‫عرفت حقيقة موته.‬
Listen, my job was to keep the peace.
‫اسمعا، كان عملي يقضي بحفظ السلام.‬
If there had been a trial,
‫لو حصلت محاكمة،‬
Jericho's and Nevermore's reputations would have been trashed.
‫لتدمّرت سمعة "جيريكو" و"نيفرمور".‬
I think the only reputation you were worried about ruining was your own.
‫أظن أن السمعة الوحيدة التي خشيت أن تتأثر‬ ‫هي سمعتك.‬
I remember Garrett bragging to me
‫أتذكّر أن "غاريت" كان يتباهى أمامي‬ ‫بأن والده كان يسيطر على المأمور.‬
One year later, you get elected mayor. Hmm.
‫بعد سنة، تمّ انتخابك عمدة.‬
No doubt with the full support of Ansel Gates.
‫لا شك أن ذاك حصل‬ ‫بدعم تام من "أنسيل غايتس".‬
I resent your implication.
‫أكره ما توحين به.‬
What I resent is that you could have prevented Garrett's death
‫ما أكرهه هو أنه كان بوسعك تجنب موت "غاريت"‬
if you had done your job when I lodged my complaint about him stalking me.
‫لو أنك قمت بعملك كما يجب‬ ‫حين تقدمت بالشكوى عن ترصّده لي.‬
But no.
‫لكن لا.‬
Men like you have no idea what it feels like not to be believed.
‫أمثالك لا يعرفون معنى ألّا يصدقهم أحد.‬
What do you want?
‫ماذا تريدان؟‬
All charges dropped.
‫إسقاط كلّ التهم.‬
My father will be released immediately
‫يُطلق سراح أبي فورًا‬
with a full and unequivocal apology from the sheriff's office.
‫ويحصل على اعتذار شامل وعلني‬ ‫من مكتب المأمور.‬
Do we have a deal?
‫هل اتفقنا؟‬
You were very impressive in there.
‫كنت مبهرة جدًا هناك.‬
When did your visions begin?
‫متى بدأت تراودك الرؤى؟‬
A few months ago.
‫قبل بضعة أشهر.‬
-Hmm. -Before I left for Nevermore.
‫قبل أن أغادر إلى "نيفرمور".‬
I'm sorry you didn't feel you could tell me.
‫يؤسفني أنك لم تشعري بأنك تستطيعين إخباري.‬
I know we've had our difficulties lately.
‫أعلم أننا واجهنا صعوبات مؤخرًا.‬
Navigating the treacherous shoals of our mother-daughter relationship.
‫المناورة لفهم مطبات العلاقة‬ ‫بين الأم وابنتها.‬
But I'm always here for you, Wednesday.
‫لكنني موجودة دائمًا لأجلك يا "وينزداي".‬
Always.
‫دائمًا.‬
Sometimes when I touch someone or something,
‫أحيانًا عندما ألمس أحدًا أو شيئًا ما…‬
I get these very violent glimpses from the past or future.
‫تراودني لمحات عنيفة جدًا‬ ‫من الماضي أو المستقبل.‬
I don't know how to control it.
‫لا أعرف كيف أتحكم بها.‬
Our psychic ability resides on the spectrum of who we are.
‫تكمن قدراتنا الغيبية في طيف شخصيتنا.‬
Given my disposition,
‫في حالتي،‬
my visions tend to be positive.
‫تميل رؤاي إلى الإيجابية.‬
That makes me a Dove.
‫وهذا يجعلني "يمامة".‬
And for someone like me? Who sees the world through a darker lens?
‫وبالنسبة إلى شخص مثلي؟‬
You're a Raven.
‫أنت "غراب".‬
Your visions are more potent, more powerful.
‫رؤاك أقوى وأكثر فعالية.‬
But without the proper training, they can lead to madness.
‫لكن من دون التدريب المناسب،‬ ‫قد تدفعك إلى الجنون.‬
If I could help you, I would, Wednesday.
‫لساعدتك لو استطعت يا "وينزداي".‬
But we're not trained by the living.
‫لكن لا يدربنا الأحياء.‬
Somebody from our bloodline reaches out from beyond to help us when we're ready.
‫شخص من سلالتنا يتواصل معنا من العالم الآخر‬ ‫لمساعدتنا حين نكون مستعدات.‬
Goody has.
‫"غودي" تواصلت معي.‬
I've seen her before.
‫رأيتها من قبل.‬
Be careful, Wednesday.
‫كوني حذرة يا "وينزداي".‬
Goody was a witch of great strength,
‫كانت "غودي" ساحرة تتمتع بقوة كبيرة،‬
but her vengeance pushed her too far,
‫لكن انتقامها جعلها تتمادى كثيرًا،‬
and even she couldn't save herself.
‫وحتى هي لم تستطع أن تنقذ نفسها.‬
Sorry about all this.
‫آسف بشأن كلّ هذا.‬
I don't hold grudges,
‫لست حاقدًا،‬
only blood debts.
‫لكنني لا أنسى دين الدم.‬
So, your daughter and my son have become…
‫إذًا ابنتك وابني قد…‬
close.
‫تقرّبا.‬
I pity any boy who gets caught in her viper's gaze,
‫أشفق على أي فتى يعلق في نظرتها الثعبانية،‬
but he must be a good egg.
‫لكن لا بد أنه فتى صالح.‬
She wouldn't tolerate anything less.
‫لن ترضى بأي شيء آخر.‬
He has his mom to thank for that.
‫يجب أن يكون ممتنًا لأمه من أجل ذلك.‬
Dad!
‫أبي!‬
I missed you so much, Dad. I missed you so much.
‫اشتقت إليك كثيرًا يا أبي.‬
Querida.
‫عزيزتي.‬
Mi amor.
‫حبيبي.‬
Don't crowd me.
‫لا تخنقني.‬
So, it's decided. Six weeks at Camp Howl.
‫إذًا تقرر الأمر.‬ ‫ستمضين ستة أسابيع في مخيم العواء.‬
-You'll need to pick which activity-- -No, I don't.
‫- عليك أن تختاري النشاطات…‬ ‫- لا، لن أفعل.‬
Because I'm not going.
‫لأنني لن أذهب.‬
Not this summer. Not ever.
‫ليس هذا الصيف. بل أبدًا.‬
If I'm meant to wolf out, then I'm going to do it on my own timeline
‫إن كان مقدرًا لي أن أتحول إلى ذئب،‬ ‫فسأفعل ذلك بوتيرتي الخاصة،‬
and not yours.
‫وليس بوتيرتك.‬
I hope that one day, you'll finally accept me for who I am.
‫لكن آمل أن تستطيعي يومًا ما‬ ‫من تقبّلي لما أنا عليه.‬
I'm proud of you, kiddo.
‫أنا فخور بك يا صغيرتي.‬
You do you.
‫افعلي ما تريدينه.‬
I'll come back and help you under one condition.
‫سأعود وأساعدك بشرط واحد.‬
-How do I know you won't run away again? -Because we both have too much to lose.
‫كيف أعرف أنك لن تهربي مجددًا؟‬
you and MorningSong are out of my life… forever.
‫ستخرجين أنت و"أغنية الصباح" من حياتي‬ ‫إلى الأبد.‬
Don't push it.
‫لا تبالغ.‬
Well, at least we can't say Parents' Weekend wasn't a nail-biter.
‫أقله لا يمكننا أن نقول‬ ‫إن عطلة أسبوع الأهالي لم تكن حماسية.‬
I knew you didn't have what it takes to be a murderer.
‫عرفت أنك لا تتمتع بالقدرة لتكون قاتلًا.‬
As much as that stings,
‫بقدر ما كلامك جارح،‬
gracias, my little death trap.
‫أشكرك يا فخ الموت الصغير.‬
As I leafed through the pages of this yearbook,
‫حين تصفحت هذا الكتاب السنوي،‬
I was reminded of all the wonderful times I had here.
‫تذكرت الأوقات المدهشة التي أمضيتها هنا.‬
But they were just that.
‫لكن هذا ما كانت عليه.‬
Mine.
‫أوقاتي.‬
You have your own path to blaze.
‫يجب أن تشقّي طريقك الخاص.‬
I don't want to be a stranger in your life, darling.
‫لا أريد أن أكون غريبة عنك يا عزيزتي.‬
If you need me for anything,
‫إن احتجت إليّ في أي شيء،‬
I'm only a crystal ball away.
‫فاتصلي بي عبر الكرة البلورية في أي وقت.‬
Thank you, Mother.
‫شكرًا يا أمي.‬
I knew it.
‫عرفت ذلك.‬
I did witness Rowan getting murdered that night.
‫شهدت مقتل "روان" تلك الليلة فعلًا.‬
Excuse me?
‫عفوًا؟‬
When Rowan appeared the next morning, it was you.
‫حين ظهر "روان" في الصباح التالي، كنت أنت.‬
When you participated in the talent show,
‫حين شاركت في عرض المواهب مع أمي،‬
not only did you impersonate Judy Garland,
‫لم تنتحلي شخصية "جودي غارلند" وحسب،‬
you became her.
‫بل أصبحت هي.‬
You're a shape-shifter.
‫أنت متحولة.‬
That's a fascinating theory.
‫هذه نظرية رائعة.‬
I'm curious to find out how Sheriff Galpin feels when I tell him.
‫ماذا سيكون شعور المأمور "غالبين"‬ ‫عندما أخبره؟‬
You won't tell a soul, Miss Addams.
‫لن تخبري أحدًا يا آنسة "آدامز".‬
And it wouldn't matter much if you did.
‫ولن يهم إن فعلت.‬
Rowan's father already knows what happened,
‫والد "روان" يعرف ماذا حصل،‬
and he fully supports my decision not to involve the authorities.
‫وهو يدعم قراري تمامًا بعدم توريط السُلطات.‬
Why would he agree to that?
‫لماذا قد يوافق على ذلك؟‬
Because Rowan was not in his right mind.
‫لأن "روان" لم يكن في كامل عقله.‬
His telekinetic abilities were driving him mad
‫قدراته على التحريك الذهني دفعته للجنون‬
and he attempted to murder you twice.
‫وحاول أن يقتلك مرتين.‬
His tragic death allowed us to rectify the situation
‫موته المأساوي سمح لنا بمعالجة الوضع‬
without casting the school or Rowan in an unflattering light.
‫من دون الإساءة إلى "روان" ولا إلى المدرسة.‬
You and Mayor Walker are the same, aren't you?
‫أنت والعمدة "واكر" متشابهان، أليس كذلك؟‬
Burying bodies to cover your dirty secrets.
‫تدفنان الجثث لتغطيا أسراركما القذرة.‬
I did what I needed to do to shield this school from controversy
‫فعلت ما فعلته لأحمي المدرسة من الجدل‬
and protect its students from harm.
‫ولأحمي طلابها من الأذى.‬
Tell that to Eugene.
‫قولي ذلك لـ"يوجين".‬
How are you protecting him?
‫كيف تحمينه؟‬
What on earth?
‫ما هذا بحق السماء؟‬